Hi! This time I'm going to show the autocomplete feature of Padre, the IDE.
As you can see I'm using version 0.87
which is a development version
from the subversion of repository.
This is going to be 0.88,
but if you are using a different version of Padre
then the feature might work slightly differently.
You can see that there is a file open here
this is one of the files of padre itself
if I start typing in some word, for example "RegisterProtocole",
which is just a name of the sub routine below that
At this point I can select the edit menu
Where we can see the autocomplete submenu
It is a ctrl+space actually
So I could click here with the mouse, or
If I just escape and go back to the editor
I can just press ctrl and space and it will auto complete the word
obviously it will do anywhere in the file
Now, if I started to(..) If I press the ctrl+space at this point
when I typed only 4 letters, then because there are couple of words that starts with "Regi..."
It will offer me to choice and then I can pick one of the words and insert it there.
Similarly I can start typing a name of a variable, for example this one
it will offer me the names of all the variables that start with "$reg..."
Obviously some people would actually prefer if it happened automatically
So, as I type it will just give me the pop-up and let me pick one of the words.
In order for that to work you have to go to the tools menu
and in the preferences select the Auto-Complete entry where the first check box is "Autocomplete always while typing".
So I check that one, save it
And now when I start typing "$re..." it already shows me a list of words
If I keep typing it will just reduce the list of words that might match this beginning
and then I can simply pick one of the words, or just keep typing, which I prefer
Or I just can press ESC in order to keep typing and not to see that pop-up.
Another option here: in the preferences, autocomplete is
"Autocomplete new methods in packages" So let's check that one and save it.
Here if I start typing a name of a sub routine
sub and then give a name to it and when I press space here
then it automatically will put the curly braces and the first command to ad shift to the "$self" variable
that's what happens in modules
If I switch over here which is a script, basically it is the main script of padre
and start typing here : "sub name ..."
the space doesn't make any difference, it doesn't do any autocompletion.
For that there is a separate option, the third one here: "Autocomplete new functions in scripts"
If I check that one
then in the script I can start typing
and then when I type, when I press the space here
It will put the curly braces here and it will put the cursor in the right place
but it doesn't put the declaration of self
because it's a sub routine, so probably there is no such variable
Let's go back to the preferences and see what else is there
Here are the numbers that allow me to control at what point auto completion will get triggered
You can change these numbers e.g. how many suggestions will there be and so on
There are two more check boxes here that are interesting. One of them is "Autocomplete brackets".
So if I check that one and I start typing here
Let's say here. And I put in curly braces
(you can't really see that) but it automatically puts in the closing one
the same happens with square brackets. You can't really see it, because of the colors of the highlighter
It's when you touch one of the endings of curly braces
square brackets, or even with parenthesis this works
So, this is what happens. Now let's see what happens if I do the same here within the sub routine
I typed in. And there you have the curly braces again.
But what happens if you put in a closing curly braces
And then before that you start typing a curly brace
Padre doesn't add you this closing one, because it sees that you already have one
For some people that's what they want, other people will prefer always to get the closing curly brace.
And for them there is the other checkbox.
Here, autocomplete. And this the checkbox: "Add another closing bracket if there already is one"
So in this case, if I check this one
If I have the closing curly and now I start an opening one
It still ads the closing one.
So it's just a matter of preference.
So that's about autocompletion
I hope you'll see the next videos as well
See you later!